The 12 Steps: A Plan of Action. We come
to CMA because of our common problem. We
stay because of our common solution. To
find long-term freedom from the grip of
addiction, we work the 12 steps of
Crystal Meth Anonymous.
One, we admitted that we were powerless
over crystal meth, and our lives had
become unmanageable. Two, came to believe
that a Power greater than ourselves could
restore us to sanity.
Three, made a decision to turn our will
and our lives over to the care of a God
of our understanding. Four, made a
searching and fearless moral inventory of
ourselves.
Five, admitted to God, to ourselves, and
to another human being the exact nature
of our wrongs. Six, were entirely ready
to have God remove all these defects of
character.
Seven, humbly asked God to remove our
shortcomings. Eight, made a list of all
persons we had harmed and became willing
to make amends to them all. Nine, made
direct amends to such people wherever
possible, except when to do so would
injure them or others.
Ten, continued to take personal
inventory, and when we were wrong,
promptly admitted it. Eleven, sought
through prayer and meditation to improve
our conscious contact with a God of our
understanding, praying only for the
knowledge of God's will for us and the
power to carry that out.
Twelve, having had a spiritual awakening
as a result of these steps, we tried to
carry this message to crystal meth
addicts and to practice these principles
in all of our affairs.
Crystal meth seemed like the answer to
our problems. Not anymore. We realize our
drug use was killing us. Once we started,
we couldn't stop. Today, to stay clean
and sober, we don't pick up, no matter
what.
When we take action, we choose faith over
fear and progress over perfection. As we
work the steps, we put spiritual
principles into motion. Surrender is an
action. It brings freedom.
Humility is an action. It brings
perspective. Gratitude is an action. It
brings contentment. This is the gift of
recovery. We awaken, our lives improve,
and we gradually move from self to
service.
We act as messengers to others who are
suffering, messengers of hope and
healing, of connection, compassion, and
yes, even joy.